Guilherme Ferreira Barros

1065- Burdett Avenue, Victoria, BC, Canada.

Email: <u>barros.guilherme21@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>GuilhermeBarros</u> Github: <u>GuilhermeBarros</u>

Personal Website: <u>www.guibarros.dev</u> Phone: (604) 446-4407

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduated in Computer Science from Veiga de Almeida University in Brazi and a diploma in Web Development from Cornerstone college in Vancouverl. I have over 7 years of proven experience as a software developer in electrical, financial industries, construction and law firms.

SKILLS

Frameworks, Libraries and Environments: Node JS, ReactJS, Bootstrap, WordPress, Jquery, Ajax, Delphi, SASS, Django, On Rails, Tailwind CSS.

Languages: JavaScript, Pascal, C#, CSS, HTML, Python, Ruby, PHP, Nodejs.

Systems and Databases: SQL, MongoDB, MariaDB, Docker, MySQL, SQLServer, FireBird.

Testing: Jest, React Testing Library, Mocha

PROJECT

SEG - Delphi and Firebird

A system that controls payments and print payments forms.

SANEPLAN - Delphi and Firebird

Civil engineering ERP that creates, controls, and administrates construction sites.

CONDCONTROL – Delphi and Firebird

The system was created to control the entry and exit of people from a commercial building.

Quiz(Group project)- React, HTML, SASS

We used an API to get the quiz questions and answers in the school project and implemented the quiz in React.

Mario(Game) - JavaScript, HTML

A game that Mario needs to get the coin around the screen

Tic Tac Toe - Java

Tic Tac Toe game that has an IA to play against a player or a 2-player mode.

Hulu Homepage Clone – React

Clone of the Hulu homepage.

Hulu Clone - React

Clone of the Hulu page with a few more functionalities added to it.

Slack Clone - React

Clone of the Slack App.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION	
Web Development	2021 - 2022
Cornerstone College	
Marketing Management Certificate	2019 - 2021
LCC ISS Language and Career School	
Business Administration Diploma	2017 - 2018
Arbutus College, Vancouver, Canada	
Bachelor Degree in Computer Science	2010 - 2015
Universidade Veiga de Almeida, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil	
Ruby on Rails	2014 - 2014
Caelum, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil	
Database Design	2014 - 2014
Coti Informática, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil	
IT Technical Support	2007 - 2009
Colégio e Escola Técnica Silva e Souza, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil	

CAREER HISTORY

Line Cook

Bellville, Victoria - Canada

2022 - Now

- Memorizing recipes, policies, procedures, and standard portion sizes
- Preparing ingredients and components of each recipe on the restaurant's menu
- Maintaining the freshness of products and rotating old products out
- Working with a team of Cooks to handle varying levels of activity
- Maintaining a clean, sanitary, and safe workspace at all times to avoid contamination

Server

White Spot, Vancouver - Canada

2021 - 2022

- Provide excellent customer services
- Greet customers and present menus
- Make suggestions based on their preferences
- Take and serve food/drinks orders
- Keep tables clean and tidy at all times
- Deliver checks and collect payments
- Cooperate and communicate with all serving and kitchen staff
- Adhere to all relevant health department rules/regulations and all customer service guidelines
 Update in July 2022

Server The Wolf and Hound, Vancouver - Canada 2019 - 2022 Provide excellent customer services Greet customers and present menus Make suggestions based on their preferences Take and serve food/drinks orders Keep tables clean and tidy at all times Deliver checks and collect payments Cooperate and communicate with all serving and kitchen staff Adhere to all relevant health department rules/regulations and all customer service guidelines Line cook 2018 - 2019 The Stable House Bistro, Vancouver - Canada Memorizing recipes, policies, procedures, and standard portion sizes Preparing ingredients and components of each recipe on the restaurant's menu Maintaining the freshness of products and rotating old products out Working with a team of Cooks to handle varying levels of activity Maintaining a clean, sanitary, and safe workspace at all times to avoid contamination Line cook 2017 - 2018 The Flying Pig, Vancouver - Canada Memorizing recipes, policies, procedures, and standard portion sizes Preparing ingredients and components of each recipe on the restaurant's menu Maintaining the freshness of products and rotating old products out Working with a team of Cooks to handle varying levels of activity Maintaining a clean, sanitary, and safe workspace at all times to avoid contamination **Software Developer** 2015 - 2017 Cast Informática LTDA, Rio de Janeiro – Rio de Janeiro – Brazil Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products. Strengthened developmental methodologies by introducing a code quality document. Technologies: C#, .net, CSS, HTML, Delphi 7, PHP, SQL Server 2008, Firebird.

Software Developer

2013 - 2015

Sanerio Engenharia – Rio de Janeiro – Rio de Janeiro – Brazil

Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.

Update in July 2022

- Maintained existing modules and designed and delivered new modules.
- Contributed to the C# code base used in the automated deployment of software on multiple virtual machines.
- Developed object-oriented software, including Construction ERP.
 Technologies: C#, .net, CSS, HTML, Delphi 7, Microsoft Project, SQL Server 2008, Firebird, MySql, PHP, Wordpress, Node.js, PostgreSQL.

Programmer 2010 - 2013

K&N Comércio e Serviços em Informática – Rio de Janeiro – Brazil

- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Drafted comprehensive reports to document bugs and design flaws.
- Designed and created eCommerce websites.

Technologies: CSS, HTML, Delphi 7, Delphi 5, Firebird, MySql, PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, JavaScript.

Intern 2009-2010

K&N Comércio e Serviços em Informática – Rio de Janeiro – Brazil

- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Drafted comprehensive reports to document bugs and design flaws.
 Technologies: CSS, HTML, Delphi 7, Delphi 5, Firebird, MySql, PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, JavaScript.